Will he really be on Mars?
真的會在火星嗎
What do you mean?
你是指什麼
That suspect.
那個嫌犯
That red figure who was seen
就是在羅伊・容格哈特博士 殺害事件裡被人所目擊的
at the murder scene of Dr. Roy Junghardt.
那個紅色人影
He will be there.
會在的
I'm really worried.
我很擔心
Don't worry.
不用擔心
The Aletheia that manages Neans wants to cover up these two murder cases.
管理涅安的真理部 要將這兩件殺人事件掩蓋下來
That sounds a lot like the Aletheia.
很像是真理部的作風
At this time,
而在這個時間點
the electromagnetic wave anomaly identical to that in Dr. Junghardt's case was observed.
觀測到了與容格哈特博士事件 相同的電磁波異常反應
This time the victim appeared to be a human.
遇害的似乎是人類
Is it possible that Nean was the one killed?
有沒有可能是涅安遇害呢
The Aletheia will only act when Neans are involved.
如果不是涅安犯行 真理部才不會有所動作
The first is on Earth,
第一件在地球
and the second is on Mars.
第二件在火星
Following the clue is the basic operation of investigation, right?
循線追查是偵辦的基本操作吧
Detective Ash.
亞許探員
I don't think that's a good enough reason for us to go to Mars.
我認為這依然不足以 成為我們來到火星的理由
That's my hunch.
這是我的直覺啦
BREAKING NEWS: MYSTERIOUS RED FIGURE WREAKS HAVOC However, interference signal appeared
(新聞快報) (神秘的紅色怪客肆虐) 但畫面上這名疑似嫌犯的人物 周圍似乎有某種雜訊
It seems we need to study your hunch.
看來有必要來研究一下 你所謂的"直覺"
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
You're so slow.
好慢
It's all your own stuff.
都是妳自己的東西
Don't get mad.
別生氣 別生氣
Brother.
哥哥
So cool.
哇 好帥喔
I want to take a picture too.
我也要拍…
Miguel, Emily.
米格爾 艾蜜莉
It's dangerous. Don't run around.
這樣很危險 不要跑來跑去
I'll pay you a visit tomorrow.
明天就會去您那裡拜訪
As soon as you see our new product…
只要您看到本公司的新產品的話…
Wait.
等等我
I need to get on.
我要上車
You're too cunning.
太狡猾了
Give it to me.
借我啦…
You're always using it. Too cunning.
都是哥哥在用 太狡猾了
Emily, you don't know how to use it.
艾蜜莉妳不會用啦
No way!
我不要
You two,
你們兩個
look over there.
看看那邊
What is that?
哇 那是什麼
That's a Vostok level second class space defense armored ship.
那是東方級2等航宙防衛裝甲艦
Vostok?
咚方
It's a warship.
是戰艦
During the great war, it served on the front lines of Mars,
大戰時期 在火星這個最前線服役
day and night in orbit fighting the Usurpers.
日以繼夜地在軌道上 與篡奪者展開激烈戰鬥
Usurpers?
篡奪者
A long time ago,
在很久很久以前
there was a group of aliens from the other side of the galaxy.
有群來自銀河彼端的外星人
Humans called them as Visitors.
人類將友善的他們稱做是"來訪者"
And then there were other aliens.
之後呢 又有別的外星人來了
However,
然而
these aliens attacked humans with extreme ferocity,
之後出現的外星人極其凶悍 對人類展開了攻擊
so humans called them as Usurpers.
於是人類將他們稱為"篡奪者"
A cosmic war broke out between humans and Usurpers
無法互相理解的人類與篡奪者
who could not understand each other.
雙方終於爆發了宇宙大戰
And Mars has become humans' last line of defense.
而火星就是人類的最終防衛線
Please look to your right.
請看看你們的右手邊
That's the remains of the weapon that was used to fight the Usurpers.
那個就是當時 與篡奪者戰鬥的武器殘骸
The fierce battles continued incessantly.
激烈的戰鬥接連不斷
Humans have developed all kinds of weapons to fight the Usurpers.
人類為了與篡奪者戰鬥 開發了各種武器
Do you know what the greatest weapon of all is?
而你們知道 其中最強最棒武器是什麼呢
Missile?
飛彈
No.
不對
Beam, the super beam.
光束 超強力的光束
The answer is
正確答案呢
Nean.
是涅安
Nean?
涅安
Neans and humans have fought together against the Usurpers before.
涅安和人類一起對抗篡奪者喔
Are you a Nean?
姐姐妳是涅安嗎
How is that possible?
她怎麼可能是啦
Neans would have scars on their faces.
涅安臉上都是有傷痕的
Uncle, you are a Nean, right?
叔叔你是涅安對吧
Have you ever killed anyone?
你有殺過人嗎
If Huey would kill, that'd be truly terrifying.
休伊會殺人啊 那還真是可怕
Don't you know?
妳不知道嗎
Neans have the Asimov Code in them.
涅安體內有著阿茲莫夫代碼喔
What?
什麼莫夫
Asimov Code.
阿茲莫夫代碼
It's programmed into my mind, warning me not to do harm to humans.
它深深地輸入在我的心裡 告誡我不可加害於人類
Although he would not kill,
他雖然不會殺人
Huey was once a soldier who had his moment in war.
但休伊以前是位軍人 在戰爭時期大展身手呢
When he was dealing with war machines…
在對付戰爭機器時…
Honey.
老公
Don't talk about such terrible things.
別聊這種可怕的事
We're on a rare trip out for fun!
我們難得旅行出來玩耶
My job now is to serve Master and Madam.
我現在的任務 就是服侍老爹和夫人
Huey.
休伊
Maybe it's about time for you to inject the Nectar.
你是不是差不多該施打涅克托了
I'm still fine.
還沒關係
Thank you for your concern, Madam.
謝謝夫人關心
Madam,
夫人
let me get you a blanket.
我幫您拿毯子來吧
Just give it to her.
妳就給她吧
You're so childish.
哇 好幼稚
I'm not an adult, but a cute kid.
我又不是大人 是可愛的小朋友啊
I understand how it feels.
我懂這種心情
You don't want to be robbed of what you like, right?
不想要喜歡的東西被人搶走對吧
That's Broma chocolate, right?
那個是布洛碼巧克力對吧
I love it too.
我也很愛吃
You know well about wars on Mars.
妳對火星戰爭很清楚呢
Not at all. I'm flattered.
沒有啦 妳太抬舉我了
Are you a military historian beauty?
難道說妳是美女歷史學家嗎
She is just a military history nerd.
只是個軍事歷史宅女
So, are you a student?
所以妳是學生嗎
Sort of.
差不多算是吧…
Could you stop taking pictures?
可以先別拍了嗎
Sorry. It's because you're very photogenic.
抱歉…因為妳很上相
What is that?
那個是什麼
My partner.
我的搭檔
That's an optical camera, right?
那是光學相機對吧
Camera? It's quite big.
相機 好大台喔
Although it's super cumbersome to use, big and easy to crash,
雖然它又重又難以維護 常常跟我鬧脾氣
it has helped me a lot.
但這孩子幫上我很多忙
It is my best partner.
是我最棒的搭檔
I'm Jill, a journalist.
我叫吉兒 是個記者
I'm investigating about Neans in today's society.
正在調查現今這個社會中 涅安是個什麼樣的存在
While there are many Neans working on Mars in reclamation and war-related industries,
雖說有很多涅安在火星 從事開墾事業與戰爭相關行業
there are also Neans who are suffering discrimination.
但也有涅安正遭受歧視
What about you?
那妳們呢
Why are you going to Wellstown?
為什麼要去威爾斯鎮
Well…
那個…
We're going after the bad guys.
在追查壞人
Bad guys?
壞人
We are military history nerds who travel with shameful story setting.
我們是帶著這種羞恥故事設定 出來旅行的軍事歷史宅女
Oh no, I'm so embarrassing.
哎呀 難為情的一面被人發現了
My name is Naomi Orthmann.
我叫直美・奧德曼
Nice to meet you.
請多指教
Come on.
快點
Rouge Redstar.
露瓊・雷德斯塔
Rouge.
露瓊…
What a beautiful name.
好美的名字
Thank you.
謝謝
Journalist.
記者
A grandma with her grandchildren.
帶著孫子的老奶奶
Travelers and their Nean servants.
旅客與他們的涅安傭人
- A salesman. - Rest assured.
-業務員 -請放心
Mysterious people.
神秘人物
Didn't Grandma say kids can't go by themselves?
奶奶不是說過 小孩子不能自己去嗎
But I want to go out and see.
可是我想去看看外面啊
Do you want to go up to the deck?
你們是想上去看台嗎
I'll take you there.
要不要帶你們去呢
What?
咦…
Great.
太好了
Really?
真的嗎
Really.
真的真的
This girl will take you there.
鏘鏘 這位姐姐會帶你們去喔
What?
咦
Let's go.
走吧走吧
Great!
太好了
No, well…
不 那個…
There's a saying, "Let the kids see the world if you love them."
不是常說要讓孩子們去見見世面嗎
Just climb the ladder to adulthood.
登上成為大人的階梯吧
I want to show this to my mom.
我要讓媽媽看看這個
Mom?
媽媽
She's in a hospital in Wellstown.
她在威爾斯鎮的醫院裡
My mom can't go outside,
媽媽沒辦法出來外面
so we'd take pictures for her.
所以我們要都拍下來給她看
Oh my, give me back my camera.
真是的 相機還我啦
Hey.
大哥
What do you do for a living?
你是做什麼工作的呢
Wait, let me guess.
等等 我猜猜看
I'm holding the first Profession Guessing competition.
我正在舉辦第一屆猜職業大賽
Are you…
大哥你啊…
Are you an assassin for some underground organization?
是地下組織的刺客嗎
Are you a member of the Mars Birdwatching Society?
是火星野鳥會的人嗎
No?
不是嗎
You look smart.
你看起來頭腦很聰明
Are you engaging in IT or management?
是IT方面 還是經營方面
Wait, let me guess.
等等 我來猜猜喔
Please give me a hint.
請給我一點提示吧
It's a job related to the body.
是要玩弄身體的工作
Is it massage-related one?
是按摩方面嗎
Let's go in.
我們進去吧
Target located.
發現目標
Commence combat operations.
開始作戰行動
Bring the target back alive.
把目標活捉回來
Understood.
瞭解
It seems those dangerous guys are coming for us.
有些好像是來找我們的 危險傢伙來了
No, not necessary.
不…這可不一定呢
It might just be a fun field trip of military nerds.
說不定他們只是來 享受歡樂的軍武遠足呢
And then he used a ray gun to char the pigeons in an instant.
然後就用光線槍 瞬間把放飛天空的鴿子打成焦炭呢
EMERGENCY STOP This bus has made an emergency stop.
(緊急停止) 這輛巴士現在為緊急停止狀態
Dear passengers…
請各位乘客
Please follow the instructions of the staff.
聽從工作人員的指示行動
The staff?
工作人員…
-Me? -Dear passengers…
-我嗎 -請各位乘客…
Give me this girl.
把這個女的交出來
As long as we get what we want, we'll keep you safe.
只要達成這個目的 我們就保証各位平安無事
Let me repeat that.
再重覆一次
Give me this girl.
把這個女的交出來
As long as we get what we want, we'll keep you safe.
只要達成這個目的 我們就保証各位平安無事…
Where did that girl go?
那個女人上哪去了
Wasn't she sitting here?
她不是坐在這裡嗎
How could we give a girl to those guys?
怎麼能把一個女孩子家 交給那些傢伙
They look like mercenaries.
他們看起來是傭兵
Didn't they say if we give them the girl, they'd keep us safe?
他們不是說只要交人 能會保証我們平安無事嗎
People like that don't keep their promises.
那種人是不會遵守諾言的
They're not going to let us get away with this.
他們是不會放過身在現場的我們的
What should we do?
那到底該怎麼辦才好
Hey, do something.
喂 你快想想辦法啊
I can do nothing.
就算你這樣對我說
It's been a long time since I drove manually.
我已經很久沒親手駕駛了
Start the bus now.
快點開動巴士
Well, manual drive…
那個…手動駕駛…
Move!
讓開
I'll deal with them.
我去解決他們
I wanted to move as inconspicuously as possible.
我想盡量低調進行移動的說
I'll take care of it.
我會好好處理的
We have no choice.
沒辦法
3 minutes.
3分鐘
3 seconds.
3秒
2 minutes.
2分鐘
90 seconds.
90秒
Understood.
瞭解
Leave it to you.
麻煩妳了
Don't move.
不准動
Don't even think about playing any tricks.
別想搞什麼花招
What?
咦
You can drive?
妳會駕駛喔
I was a racer when I was young.
老娘年輕時可是車手
They called me the Lady Speed.
江湖上都稱呼我為"音速貴婦"
120 seconds. You're 30 seconds out.
120秒 超時了30秒
So strict.
好嚴格
Please make sure you keep to the time.
請務必遵守時間
You two,
妳們兩個
what did you do?
到底是做了什麼
Just a scratch.
只是擦傷
Luckily, you just got hit by a stray bullet.
還好只是被流彈打到而已
Are you alright?
您沒事吧
You are useless!
這個沒用的東西
You can't even protect your master.
居然保護不了主人
You got shot too, right?
你也中彈了吧
The bullet went all the way through without hitting the injection port.
子彈都穿過去了 也沒傷到注射口
You'll be fine.
應該沒事
So you are a doctor.
原來答案是醫生啊
There's a forest over there.
那邊有片森林
Okay.
好
Everyone, hold on tight.
所有人都抓穩了
Or you'll be thrown out.
不然會被甩出去喔
(Episode 2: Wander in the Labyrinth)
(2 逃走迷路)
No way.
不行
The whole cable system is broken.
電纜整組壞了
What do we do now?
這下怎麼辦
It would be bad if I didn't make it to Wellstown today.
我今天要是沒辦法 抵達威爾斯鎮就糟了啊
There should be a military base that was used during the war.
這裡的深處應該有 戰爭時期所使用的軍事基地
Perhaps we can find a substitute.
或許能夠找到替代品
I'll go find it.
我去找找
You know a lot.
妳懂得還真多呢
After all, I'm a military history nerd.
畢竟是軍事歷史宅女嘛
We need an RG200 cable.
需要的是RG200電纜
Please find the same type.
麻煩妳找一樣的來
Understood.
瞭解
You should go with her.
你也給我一起去
What?
咦
Me too.
我也去
I'll go as well.
我也一起去
You stay here.
妳留在這裡
What?
咦
I want to go.
我要去
What if they show up again?
要是他們又出現的話怎麼辦
Rouge, you stay.
露瓊 看家
Woof.
汪
Amazing! When did you guys take this?
好厲害 你們什麼時候拍到的
These guys must be SOA, right?
這群傢伙應該是SOA吧
What's SOA?
SOA是什麼
Sons of Ares,
阿瑞斯之子(Suns Of Ares)
abbreviated as SOA.
簡稱SOA
It's a civilian security company.
是民間警備公司
Simply put, they're mercenaries.
簡單來說就是傭兵
They are employed by someone.
他們受雇於某人
YO… HEI…
YO…HEI…
It's a really good shot, anyway.
話說回來 真的拍得很好呢
This one can win the Pulitzer Award.
這張能得普立茲獎喔
I can take a picture like that.
這種照片我也拍得出來
You're not even close.
妳還差得遠呢
Wait for me.
等等我
Go after the bad guys.
"在追查壞人"
I think you were not lying.
看來並不是在騙人呢
I was lying.
那是騙人的
We were saved thanks to you.
多虧有妳 我們才能得救
Thank you.
謝謝妳
I was just following orders.
我只不過…是奉命行事罷了
You are free.
妳是自由的
Free?
自由
Me?
我嗎
Freedom is the ability to make your own choices.
自由就是能自己做出選擇
Right?
對吧
Let's go get some amazing pictures and show them to your brother, okay?
我們去拍很棒的照片 向哥哥證明妳很厲害好不好
Hmm.
嗯
Let's go.
走吧
Someone's here…
有人…
Nean
涅安
fought with humans, right?
與人類同共奮戰…是嗎
Thank you.
謝謝您
Wow.
哇…
What is this?
這是什麼
The Usurper's war machine,
簒奪者的戰爭機器
commonly known as cylinder head.
俗稱"汽缸頭"
As long as it's not activated,
只要不讓它啟動的話…
it's just a piece of scrap metal.
它就只是塊廢鐵而已
What are you doing?
你在做什麼
Investigating the battlefield ruins.
調查戰場遺跡
This area used to be a fierce battleground.
這一帶是激戰地呢
This won't work either.
這個也不行了
I can't exchange it for money.
換不了錢呢
Who are you?
你是誰
Emily.
艾蜜莉
What happened?
怎麼了
Emily is missing.
艾蜜莉不見了
What?
咦
Well, Rouge is missing too.
說起來露瓊也不見了
Did she run away?
該不會是逃走了吧
Emily.
艾蜜莉
Don't move.
不要動
This model responds to moving objects.
這種型號的會對移動物體有所反應
Just stay quiet like this.
就這樣保持安靜
Soon it will go back into sleep mode.
不久後它就會再度進入休眠模式
What?
咦
Let's run.
快逃
Found it.
找到了
This
這東西…
is the cylinder head.
是汽缸頭啊
What's wrong?
怎麼了
Emily.
艾蜜莉…
Damn.
可惡
Why is there something like this here?
怎麼會有這種東西
Is it…
難不成…
Emily.
艾蜜莉
Rouge.
露瓊
I've fixed it.
修好了
Start the bus now. That dangerous thing is coming.
快開車 危險的傢伙要來了
Who are you?
你哪位
No way.
不會吧
I'm setting off.
要出發了
Rouge, where did you go?
露瓊 妳跑去哪裡了
The attack was bounced off.
被彈開了
Get a bit closer.
再貼近一點
Get inside the shield.
衝進防護罩裡面
You're always forcing me to do something like that.
老是這樣強人所難
Hold on tight.
都抓穩了
Well, where's Rouge?
那個 露瓊姐姐呢
Maybe we should head back.
果然還是回去比較好吧
Well, she should be fine.
這個嘛…她應該沒問題的
You are pretty good.
這種感覺…挺不錯的耶
Who are you?
你哪位啊
Did you take this picture?
這是妳拍的嗎
You're quite impressive.
很厲害嘛
I also have an older brother.
我也有個哥哥
So I know how you feel.
所以我能懂妳的心情
Thank you.
謝謝妳
You've grown up.
妳長大了呢
The kid has seen the world and successfully climbed the ladder to adulthood.
孩子去見完世面 成功爬上成為大人的階梯了
Right.
是啊